http://www.bbsi.com/privacy-policy/

BBSI Online Privacy Policy
1. Overview
Barrett Business Services, Inc. (“BBSI,” “we,” “us,” and “our”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Notice describes the types of Personal Information we may collect from you, that you may provide when you visit the MyBBSI.com website at https://mybbsi.com/
(“Site”), and that you may provide in electronic messages between you and this Site. It also describes our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that Information.
Whenever you visit our Site, we will collect some information from you automatically simply by you visiting and navigating through this site, and some voluntarily when you submit information using forms that may be available on the Site. Through this Site, we will collect information that can or may identify you and/or your activity on the Site.
Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your Personal Information and how we will handle it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, do not use the Site. By accessing or using this Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy.
BBSI may change this Privacy Policy at any time, at its discretion. Your continued use of this Site after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the Privacy Policy periodically for updates.
This Privacy Policy is subject to and governed by the BBSI Website Terms of Use (“Terms of Use”) available at the Site https://portal.mybbsi.com
2. Types of Personal Information that BBSI collects
BBSI collects the following categories of personal information about visitors of our Site. For each category of information, we identify examples of the category, the business purposes for which we use the information in that category, the categories of sources from which the information is collected, and the categories of third parties with whom we have shared the information in the last 12 months.
Category of Personal Information
Personal Identifiers & Contact Information
Examples
Name, mailing address, email address, phone number
Business Purpose(s) for Which Information is Used
· Responding to inquiries submitted through the Site;
· Providing you with data, products, or services that you request from us (for example, when you provide your email address through the “Contact Us” form, we are able to use your email address to respond to your comment or question personally);
· Communicating with you regarding our products and services, including for marketing purposes;
· Notifying you about changes to our Site or any products or services we offer or provide though it;
· Fulfilling any other purpose for which you provide this information to us; and
· Verifying and responding to consumer requests.
Categories of Sources from Which Information Received
Directly from you when you provide it to us, such as by filling out forms on the Site or when we ask you for this information after you report a problem with our Site or request a demo.
Categories of Third Parties to Whom Info Was Disclosed in Last 12 Months
We share this information with third party service providers the provide us the following services (also see Section 5 of this Privacy Policy below):
· hosting our Site;
· designing and operating the Site features;
· administrative services;
· analytics;
· payment processing; and
· communications services.
Except as described above, we do not share this information with any other third party, unless with your consent, if we are required to do so by law enforcement or government agency, or for the purpose of defending or prosecuting legal claims.
Category of Personal Information
Internet Activity
Examples
Date and time of your visit to this Site; webpages visited or accessed on the Site; links clicked on the Site; browser ID; browser type; device ID; operating system type; form information downloaded; domain name from which our Site was accessed; and cookies (See Section 4 of this Privacy Policy below)
Business Purpose(s) for Which Information is Used
· Improving and optimizing the Site experience for all visitors;
· Understanding the demographics of our Site visitors;
· Understanding, anticipating, and responding to user needs (for example, if we learn of heightened interest in certain aspects of BBSI’s projects, we are likely to highlight that information on the Site home page);
· Operating and maintaining the Site;
· Tailoring content of the Site to the needs of the specific browser used to access the Site;
· Enforcing or applying our Website Terms of Use;
· Detecting security incidents;
· Debugging to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality of the Site;
· Protecting against malicious or illegal activity and prosecuting those responsible; and
· Verifying and responding to consumer requests.
Categories of Sources from Which Information Collected
· Directly from you when you provide it to us;
· Automatically as you navigate through the Site; and
· Through cookies, Google Analytics, and Facebook Pixel (See Section 4 of this Privacy Policy below).
Categories of Third Parties to Whom Info Was Disclosed in Last 12 Months
We share this information with third party service providers the provide us the following services (also see Section 5 of this Privacy Policy below):
· hosting our Site;
· designing and operating the Site features;
· administrative services;
· analytics; and
· communications services.
Except as described above, we do not share this information with any other third party, unless with your consent, if we are required to do so by law enforcement or government agency, or for the purpose of defending or prosecuting legal claims.
Category of Personal Information
Geolocation Data
Examples
Internet Protocol (IP) Address. The IP address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer.
Business Purpose(s) for Which Information is Used
· Directing Internet traffic to you;
· Improving and optimizing the Site experience for all visitors;
· Understanding the demographics of our Site visitors;
· Detecting security incidents;
· Debugging to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality of the Site;
· Protecting against malicious or illegal activity and prosecuting those responsible; and
· Verifying and responding to consumer requests.
Categories of Sources from Which Information Received
· Automatically as you navigate through the Site; and
· Through cookies, Google Analytics, and Facebook Pixel (See Section 4 of this Privacy Policy below).
Categories of Third Parties to Whom Info Was Disclosed in Last 12 Months
We share this information with third party service providers the provide us the following services (also see Section 5 of this Privacy Policy below):
· hosting our Site;
· designing and operating the Site features;
· administrative services; and
· analytics
Except as described above, we do not share this information with any other third party, unless with your consent, if we are required to do so by law enforcement or government agency, or for the purpose of defending or prosecuting legal claims.
Category of Personal Information
Transactions & Correspondence
Examples
Records and copies of your correspondence (including emails), if you contact us through the Site; your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete; and details of transactions you carry out through our Site.
Business Purpose(s) for Which Information is Used
· Improving and optimizing the Site experience for all visitors;
· Providing you with data, products, or services that you request from us;
· Carrying out our obligations and enforcing our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection;
· Fulfilling any other purpose for which you provide this information to us; and
· Verifying and responding to consumer requests.
Categories of Sources from Which Information Received
Directly from you when you communicate with us or engage in transactions through the Site.
Categories of Third Parties to Whom Info Was Disclosed in Last 12 Months
We share this information with third party service providers the provide us the following services (also see Section 5 of this Privacy Policy below):
· hosting our Site;
· designing and operating the Site features;
· administrative services;
· analytics;
· payment processing; and
· communications services.
Except as described above, we do not share this information with any other third party, unless with your consent, if we are required to do so by law enforcement or government agency, or for the purpose of defending or prosecuting legal claims.
BBSI collects the following categories of personal information when submitting employment inquiries on this Site:
The Site allows you to submit employment inquiries, which involve providing us the following categories of personal information:
Personal identifies & contact information (such as your name, address, phone number, and email address)
Employment history (current and past employment information)
Education history (such as degrees or certificates obtained, schools attended, etc.);
Information about your perceived successes and failures;
Location where you are interested in working;
Why you believe you would be a good fit for BBSI; and
Other information you provide in your cover letter and resume.
When you submit the above information on the Site in connection with employment inquiries, BBSI may use this information to consider your candidacy for employment and communicate with you regarding your inquiry. However, merely submitting an employment inquiry through the Site does not guarantee that BBSI will consider you for employment or review any of the information you submit. BBSI is not required to consider your employment inquiry.
3. Do we sell any of your personal information?
BBSI does NOT sell your personal information, including the data of any minors. We do not sell or otherwise trade or disclose for valuable monetary or non-monetary consideration the personal information that we collect from our Site visitors at any point or under any circumstance.
4. Use of cookies and other tracking technologies
Cookies
Cookies are small text files that a website server (such as BBSI’s or its chosen web hosting company server) may transfer to a user’s computer that reside there for either the duration of the browsing session (session cookies) or on a permanent (until deleted) basis (persistent cookies) that may be used to identify a user, a user’s machine, or a user’s behavior. We make use of cookies under the following circumstances and for the following reasons:
Compile data about site traffic to offer a better Site experience
Understand and save visitor preferences for future visits
When accessing a cookie, BBSI’s server reads a number associated with a browser, but is unable to determine any data about a user. With that number, our web server can tailor its content to the needs of the specific browser, and we can optimize the Site for your use.
Google Analytics Advertising FeaturesWe may have the following Google Analytics Advertising Features Implemented: Demographics and Interest reporting, Remarketing, GDN Impression Reporting and Double Click Campaign Manager. These features collect data using Google advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers. BBSI and third-party vendors use these first-party cookies to access the success of online marketing campaigns, inform future campaigns and improve usability on the Site. To learn how to opt-out of the Google Analytics Advertising Features we use, please see Google Analytics’ currently available op-outs for the web: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.
Facebook Pixel
We are able to identify which Facebook users are engaging with our content through the use of Facebook Pixel. With the data collected, we are able to optimize our Facebook and/or Instagram advertisements to the audience that has shown interest in our product(s) or service(s). Facebook reserves the right to share the information you provide. If you do not want Facebook to share your information, you should remove it from Facebook.
Do Not Track settings
Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that users can set if they do not want web services to collect information about their online activity. However, there is currently no universal standard for sending and receiving DNT signals. Due to this lack of universal standard, it would be impossible for us to promise that we comply with all known and unknown DNT standards.
Therefore, we do not respond to DNT signals or other mechanisms that provide a choice regarding the collection of personal information about activities over time and across different Web sites or online services. If a universal standard for DNT becomes available, we may revisit our DNT Policy.
5. Third parties providing services on our behalf
We use third parties to host the Site, design and operate the Site features, and perform administrative, analytics, payment processing, and communications services. Services these third parties provide include enabling BBSI to send you email newsletters and providing information to BBSI about the use of the Site and viewing of our content. We may disclose your Information to these companies so they can carry out these services for BBSI. These companies are bound by contractual obligations to keep the information confidential and to implement and maintain reasonable security measures to safeguard the information.
6. Business Transfers
In the event the Company sells or transfers a particular portion of its business assets, consumer information may be one of the business assets transferred as part of the transaction. If substantially all of the assets of the Company are acquired, consumer information may be transferred as part of the acquisition.
7. Compliance with law/safety:
The Company may disclose specific personal information based on a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to comply with or conform to the law or that such disclosure is necessary to protect the users of our Website, the site itself, or the public.
8. Your Rights as a California Consumer
If you are a California resident, you have the following rights:
Request to Know (Type I): The right to request, up to 2 times in a 12-month period, that we identify to you (1) the categories of personal information we have collected, disclosed or sold about you in the last 12 months, (2) the categories of sources from which the personal information was collected, (3) the business purpose for which we use this information, and (4) the categories of third parties with whom we share or have shared your personal information in the last 12 months;
Request to Access: The right to request, up to 2 times in a 12-month period, that we disclose to you, free of charge, the specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you in the last 12 months;
Request to Delete: The right to request, up to 2 times in a 12-month period, that we delete personal information that we collected from you, subject to certain exceptions;
Request to Opt-Out: The right to opt-out of the sale of your personal information to third parties;
The right to designate an authorized agent to submit one of the above requests on your behalf; and
The right to not be discriminated against in receiving different or less favorable pricing, service or financial incentive for exercising any of the above rights.
If you are a California-based employee or job applicant, you do not currently have any of the above rights with respect to any of your personal information that BBSI has collected for employment-related purposes.
9. How to submit a Request
If you are a California resident, you can submit a Request to Know, Access, or Delete by any of the two options below:
Submit an online request on our Site at https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/04a0d00e-2dfe-48e7-8f76-0873083c0e4d/c9531035-da2d-480e-9b98-adb4bf1623d9.html
Call our privacy toll-free line at (1) 888-914-9661 and use the PIN # 151 733.
10. How we will verify that it is really you submitting the above request
If you are a California resident, when you submit a Request to Know, Access or Delete through one of the methods provided above, we will ask you to provide some information in order to verify your identity and respond to your request. Specifically, we will need you to provide your name, email, phone number, IP address, and device ID.  [AND / OR] If your sole interaction with us was as a website visitor, then in order to verify your identify, we will need to ask you to provide your name, email, phone number, IP address, device ID, browser ID, and/or cookie ID.
11. Responding to Right to Know, Access, and Delete Requests
We endeavor to respond to a verifiable consumer request within forty-five (45) days of its receipt. If we require more time (up to 45 days or 90 days total from the date we receive your request), we will inform you of the reason and extension period in writing. We will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option. Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding our receipt of your verifiable consumer request. The response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable consumer request unless it is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.
12. Responding to your consumer request to opt-out of the sale of your personal information
We will act upon a verifiable consumer request to opt-out within fifteen (15) days of its receipt. We will notify all third parties to whom we have sold personal information within 90 days of our receipt of your request that you have exercised your right to opt-out and instruct them not to further sell the information. We will notify you when this has been completed by mail or electronically, at your option.
A request to opt-out need not be a verifiable consumer request. However, we may deny a request to opt-out if we have a good faith, reasonable, and documented belief that a request to opt-out is fraudulent. If we deny your request to opt-out, we shall inform you of our decision not to comply and provide an explanation as to why we believe the request is fraudulent.
13. How to authorize an agent to act on your behalf
If you are a California resident, you can authorize someone else as an Authorized Agent who can submit a request on your behalf. To authorize an agent, you must either (a) execute a valid, verifiable, and notarized Power of Attorney or (b) provide other written authorization that we can then verify. When we receive a consumer request submitted on your behalf by an Authorized Agent, that person will be asked to provide written proof that they have your permission to act on your behalf, and we will also contact you and ask you for information to verify your own identity directly with us and not through your Authorized Agent.
14. Children under the age of 16
Our Site is not intended for children under 16 years of age and we do not knowingly collect information about children under age 16. No one under age 16 may provide any personal information on the Site. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If you are under 16, do not use or provide any information on this Site. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 16 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our databases. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us at the email address below.
15. How we protect the information that we collect
The protection of the information that we collect about visitors to this Site is of the utmost importance to us and we take every reasonable measure to ensure that your information is protected from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure, including:
We keep automatically collected data and voluntarily collected data separate at all times.
We use internal encryption on all data stores that house voluntarily captured data.
We use commercially reasonable tools and techniques to protect against unauthorized access to our systems.
We restrict access to private information to those who need such access in the course of their duties for us.
Unfortunately, the internet is not completely secure. Although we are working to protect your Information, we cannot guarantee the security of your Information either in transmission or when stored. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site.
16. Links to other websites and services
We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from the Site, including the information or content contained therein. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites or services.
17. Questions about this policy
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you should contact us by phone at 800-494-5669 or by mail at Barrett Business Services, Inc., Attn: BBSI Inquiries, 8100 NE Parkway Drive, Suite 200, Vancouver, WA 98662
18. Consent to Terms and Conditions and Changes
By using this Site, you consent to all Terms and Conditions expressed in this Privacy Policy.
From time to time we may modify and/or update this Privacy Policy and so we encourage you to check back on a regular basis to determine if any changes have been made.
